sampath.lk 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy - Sampath Bank PLC

## Introduction

Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to Sampath Bank PLC and to comply with any applicable data protection and privacy laws. We want to ensure that you fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This online privacy statement explains how Sampath Bank PLC collects, uses and shares information from or about you when you visit a web site, and how we collect information based on your interactions with our online systems. This privacy policy applies to all Sampath Bank web sites.

## Personal Information

We will not collect personal information like names or addresses when you visit our website unless you choose to provide it to us. If you register for an online banking system or payment system, you may be asked for information that helps to identify you, such as your name, email address, and organization. The information you are asked to provide is used for technical and customer administration of the site only and is not shared with third parties.

## Non-personally identifiable information

We automatically gather and store certain technical information about your visit. This information never identifies who you are. The information we collect and store about your visit is listed below:

  * IP Addresses: The Internet protocol (IP) address which is assigned to your computer whenever you are access the bank’s web sites will be recorded.
  * Browser type: The type of browser (for example, Internet Explorer, Firefox) which you are using for accessing the bank’s web sites will be recorded.
  * OS version: The type of operating system (for Microsoft, Linux) which you are using for accessing the bank’s web sites will be recorded.
  * Date & Time: Date and time which you are using for accessing the bank’s web sites will be recorded.
  * Visited pages: Name of the visited web page will be recorded.

This information is used to help us make the site more useful for you. With this data we learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We also use this data to optimize the site's technical design specifications and/or identify system performance or problem areas. This information is used as a source of anonymous statistical data and is retained for a period of five years; it is shared only when required for law enforcement purposes.

## Cookies

A 'cookie' is a small bit of code stored on your computer's hard drive that enables you to manage your subscriptions and online profile. By setting this cookie, the web sites will remember you the next time you visit and won't have to bother you by asking questions you have already answered (like address information). The Sampath Bank does not use 'cookies' to get information about you or your use of our website.

## Security

When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a username, password and credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol and there are variety of procedures and security technologies to protect customer’s personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

It is your responsibility to keep your username and password confidential which is used for accessing online banking system sites of the Sampath Bank. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always properly log out before leaving the computer.

Sampath Bank would like to remind all its Internet Banking customers that the Bank's Internet Banking service does not direct customers to change passwords in any way outside the usual method, or use any external websites.

It is your responsibility to verify the URL before you access any published information on the internet by Sampath Bank PLC.

## Making sure information is accurate

Keeping your account information accurate and up to date is very important. If your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please use the Contact Us option on our Site, or call or write to us at the telephone numbers or appropriate address for changes listed on your account statements, records, online or other account materials.

## Linking to other sites

We may provide links to non Sampath Bank websites, such as Reuters and payment gateway customers. If you follow links to websites not controlled by Sampath Bank, you should review their privacy policies and other terms, as they may be different from those of our sites.

## How to Contact Us

If you have a question about the way your information is used in connection with this website or about the sampath Bank privacy policy and information practices, you may go to the Contact US

## Changes to the Online Privacy Policy

This Online Privacy Notice is subject to change. Please review it periodically. When we post changes to this Statement, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this statement. Any changes to this policy will become effective when we post the revised policy on the Site. Your use of the Site following these changes means that you accept the revised policy.
